# Oleksandr Ratushnyi

Senior front-end engineer

Kremenchuk, Ukraine T: +380679340776 E: <u>alexander.ratushnyi@gmail.com</u>
G: https://github.com/a1exalexander

L: <u>alexander-ratushnyi</u>

W: https://sashkoratushnyi.com

# **Summary**

A skilled Front-end Developer from Ukraine with over 6 years of experience, my main stack is React + TypeScript. I am also experienced in Node.js development, so I'm actually a full-stack, but at heart I'm a front-end. Specialized in full-stack javascript development, development discovery, web architecture team management, development processes, and development delivery. I have successfully developed and managed over 22 projects from inception to production, with more than 15 handled independently. Additionally, I have experience in teaching and creating courses in front-end development.

# **Technologies**

Javascript, HTML, CSS, TypeScript, React, Next.js, Remix, Vue, Nuxt, Node.js, NestJS, Fastify, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Prisma, Redis, Redux, MobX, MVC, DDD, CA, FSD, OOP, SDLC

# **Professional Experience**

# **Merge**

(2018 - Present) Full-stack Developer / CTO / Co-founder

Engaged in the development of web applications primarily in the fintech and SaaS sectors.

Responsibilities included managing in-house developers, setting up the company's processes, hiring, and mentoring of developers. Key projects involved developing innovative financial technology solutions and scalable SaaS platforms.

#### **Merge Academy**

(2022 - 2023) Course Author / Teacher

I created a front-end development course program and started teaching it, developed a website for the academy and helped with setting up automation of course processes.

#### **WiseAlpha**

(2020) Front-end Developer

Trading and Technology for the Corporate Bond Market. Developed new features on the old and good Backbone.

### **Beetroot Academy**

(2019 - 2021) Teacher

Taught a course on front-end development and successfully released two groups of students.

#### **Freelance**

(2017 - 2021) Front-end Developer

Part-time freelance role involving diverse projects, showcasing adaptability and skill in various front-end technologies.

# **Education**

(2014) Kharkiv National University of Internal Affairs - Hold a Bachelor's Degree in Jurisprudence (2017) Graduated from the National Academy of Internal Affairs. Hold a Master's Degree in Jurisprudence

Languages: English (Upper-intermediate), Ukrainian (Native)

Hobbies: Photography, photo retouching, riding a bicycle, pizza cooking

Portfolio: https://sashkoratushnyi.com